Tyler Friedman

tyler@idealogs.org | Chicago, IL | tylerfriedman.org

OBJECTIVE

A talented, self-motivated IT professional with entrepreneurial spirit seeks the position of Entry Level Web Developer in a thriving company. Comes with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Mathematics and two years independent experience of full-stack Django web development.

EDUCATION

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel

Completed 4 credits towards a Master of Science in Electrical Engineering Graduate Student Scholarship (100% tuition waiver and living stipend)

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Bachelor of Science with Distinction, Computer Science and Mathematical Sciences

Sep 2010 – Apr 2015 nputer Science and Mathematical Sciences GPA: 3.72/4.00

SKILLS

Web Frameworks: Django

Languages: Python, C, C++, C#, MATLAB, Erlang, HTML, CSS, jQuery, LaTeX

Applications: Git, PDB, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, memcached, Celery, RabbitMQ, nginx, gunicorn, borg

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Programming & Data Structures, Computer Game Design, Databases, Algorithms, Coding Theory, Operating Systems, Computer Security, Distributed Functional Programming, Intro to Combinatorics, Probability Theory

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Idealogical Foundation, Inc., Flagstaff, AZ

Founder, Lead Developer

Sep 2017 – Present

Oct 2016 - Mar 2017

GPA: 94.5/100

- Built a crowdsourcing website for understanding controversial topics (idealogs.org) in Django
- Mastered fundamentals of full-stack web development including: M-V-T architecture, ORMs, rapid prototyping, responsive design, search, caching, asynchronous task management, VPS hosting, deduplicating backups, and profiling
- Developed idea from infancy to production without prior web development experience or outside help
- Invented a new model for aggregating and refining contextual information
- Managed all aspects of the project including: engineering, financing, corporation formation, and trademark application

Coconino Community College, Flagstaff, AZ

Adjunct Lecturer, Mathematics

Jan 2018 – Aug 2019

- Taught algebra to students that struggle considerably with the subject
- Devised lectures with focus on emotional aspects of learning to make courses approachable
- Brought positive energy and humor to lectures to keep students engaged
- Emphasized strong studying habits and pushed students to make connections between time investment and achievement

Transcaucasian Trail Association, Svaneti, Republic of Georgia

Project Manager

Jun 2018 – Sep 2018

- Provided logistical support to project attempting to connect Black and Caspian Seas via one long-distance hiking trail through the Caucasus Mountains (transcaucasiantrail.org)
- Stewarded the project home base and operations center to keep project running efficiently
- Organized food and gear shopping, and managed crews when they were not in the field

Crew Leader Jun 2017 – Sep 2017

- Designed and constructed reroutes of deteriorating hiking trails
- Supervised crews of 8-12 international volunteers on 8-day projects in a backcountry environment
- Managed diverse personalities from varied ages and backgrounds into cohesive working units
- Constantly monitored health, energy, and morale of group to ensure a safe and productive working environment
- Enforced safety-first practices at all times to maintain integrity of the project